Kraushaar Galleries
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Incoming Letters, circa 1901-1944, Series 2:; (boxes 10-26; 16.25 ft.)
  - Brooklyn Museum, 1943 (Box 24, Folder 40)
    (an exhibition of The Eight)
  - C, General, 1943 (Box 24, Folder 41)
  - Carnegie Institute, 1943 (Box 24, Folder 42)
  - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1943 (Box 24, Folder 43)
  - D, General, 1943 (Box 24, Folder 44)
  - E, General, 1943 (Box 24, Folder 45)
    (Fritz Ehrenfest; Jane Ehrenfest)
  - F, General, 1943 (Box 24, Folder 46)
  - G, General, 1943 (Box 24, Folder 47)
    (Edith Glackens; Lloyd Goff; Nelson Goodman; Earle Grant)
  - Wm. E. Goodridge & Son, 1943 (Box 24, Folder 48)
  - H, General, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    (Dalzell Hatfield; John Heliker discussing conflict of creativity and commercial success)
  - Hartell, John, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - I, General, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - J, General, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - K, General, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - L, General, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    (Isabel Nagle Lachaise; Richard Lahey; William F. Laporte; Little Gallery owned by Vincent Price and George Macready; Robert Locher; Charles Locke)
  - M, General, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    (postcard from Reginald Marsh; Milwaukee Art Institute)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - N, General, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    (Thomas W. Nason; Elizabeth S. Navas; Woldemar Neufeld)
  - O, General, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - P, General, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    (Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts; Commonwealth of Pennsylvania notifying John Kraushaar that he is appointed to appraise the paintings in the estate of Augusta W. Demuth following the death of Charles Demuth; Phillips Memorial Gallery; Eugenie Prendergast)
  - R, General, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    (Boardman Robinson; Iver Rose)
  - Ruellan, Andrée, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - S, General, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    (John Sloan concerning his health and sales of White Way and Bleeker Street Saturday Night; Alix W. Stanley)
  - Southam, H. S., 1943 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Sturgis, Katharine, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - T, General, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Toledo Museum of Art, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - U, General, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - V, General, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - W, General, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    (Maynard Walker; Nan Watson; Esther Williams; Caroline Willson; Donald B. Willson)
  - X-Y-Z, General, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 23-24)
  - Receipts, 1943 (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - A, General, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - Art Institute of Chicago, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - B, General, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 29)
    (Jozef Bakos; Gifford Beal; Reynolds Beal; Rosalie Berkowitz; Copeland C. Burg)
  - C, General, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - Carnegie Institute, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - D, General, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - E, General, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - F, General, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 34)
    (William Dean Fausett; Vaughn Flannery; Emma L. Frankenberg)
  - G, General, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 35)
    (Earle Grant)
  - Wm. E. Goodridge & Son, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 36)
  - H, General, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 37)
    (Ernst Halberstadt; John Heliker concerning a trip to Harborside, Maine, and relating story of visits to the area by Maurice Prendergast years earlier)
  - Hartell, John, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 38)
  - Hatfield, Dalzell, and Ruth Hatfield, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 39)
  - I, General, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 40)
    (Institute of Modern Art in Boston)
  - J, General, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 41)
  - K, General, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 42)
  - L, General, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 43)
  - M, General, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 44)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 45)
    (Sport in American Art exhibition)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 46)
    (Romantic Painting in America and Art in Progress exhibitions)
  - N, General, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 47)
  - O, General, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 48)
  - P, General, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 49)
  - Q, General, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 50)
  - R, General, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 51)
    (Iver Rose; Andrée Ruellan discussing commercial work)
  - Robinson, Boardman, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 52)
  - S, General, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 53)
    (Karl Schrag requesting an interview to show his work; John Sloan and Helen Farr Sloan concerning their marriage and John Sloan's purchase of McSorley's Back Room and Jefferson Market Jail; Alix W. Stanley; Katharine Sturgis)
  - T, General, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 54)
  - Toledo Museum of Art, 1944 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Train, Helen, 1944 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - U, General, 1944 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    (Frederick Dwight Kirsch of the University of Nebraska)
  - V, General, 1944 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - W, General, 1944 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    (Michael Waskowsky; Nan Watson; Esther Williams; Witte Memorial Museum)
  - X-Y-Z, General, 1944 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1944 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Receipts, 1944 (Box 26, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1945-1968, Series 3:; (boxes 26-53; 27.75 ft.)
  This series, which documents the operation of the gallery from 1945 to 1968, is the largest in the collection and rich in artist correspondence. In addition to correspondence with the artists mentioned in the description for Series 2, substantial correspondence with Humbert Albrizio, Bernard Arnest, Peggy Bacon, Louis Bouché, Leonard DeLonga, Kenneth Evett, Ernst Halberstadt, Tom Hardy, John Hartell, John Heliker, Robert Laurent, James Lechay, Carl Morris, James Penney, and Vernon Smith can be found here.
  Correspondence with Eugenie Prendergast, following the death of Charles Prendergast in 1948, documents the galleries' continued commitment to the work of the Prendergast brothers and Eugenie Prendergast's decision to end the business relationship with Kraushaar Galleries around 1961. Substantial correspondence with Ira Glackens after the death of Edith in 1955 documents the galleries' continued representation of work by William Glackens. William Dean Fausett and Vaughn Flannery were both prolific correspondents throughout the 1940s, and their letters provide details concerning many aspects of their work. The Kraushaars' long and happy association with John Sloan also continues to be documented here, up to and beyond Sloan's death in 1951. Correspondence from 1947 records Guy Pène Du Bois's decision to seek another dealer, but that the split was reasonably amicable is evinced by Antoinette Kraushaar's continued contact with the family through Du Bois's daughter and artist in her own right, Yvonne.
  The series documents some strong and mutually beneficial relations between Kraushaar Galleries and various art institutions and the individuals responsible for developing their collections. In addition to the institutions mentioned in the description for Series 1, institutions and individuals that are particularly well represented include the Toledo Museum of Art, Frederick Dwight Kirsch and the University of Nebraska Art Department, Alix W. Stanley and the New Britain Institute, and Ralph L. Wilson and Lehigh University.
  To retain context, there is occasionally some slight overlap between years in cases where a letter from the end of one year was originally filed with one from the beginning of the next. Considerable interfiling of papers with acid-free paper was required in this series as many of the outgoing letters are printed on highly acidic paper. To reduce the bulk that this precaution added to the collection, outgoing letters to a single correspondent were often grouped together; hence strict chronological order has not been retained.
  Additional correspondence dating from 1945-1968 is found in Series 6.1.
  Records are arranged chronologically and alphabetically by correspondent within each year; folders for "Miscellaneous Notes," "Bills," and "Receipts" are filed at the end of the year to which they relate. A group of records dated 1950 to 1951, to and from various correspondents concerning loans for a William Sommer exhibition at Kraushaar Galleries in 1951, are filed at the end of 1950. Records for 1965 were not transferred to the Archives of American Art, with the exception of several pieces of correspondence. Similarly, there are very few letters from 1968.
  - Ad-Arn, General, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Art-Ay, General, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    (Alicia Atkinson)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Art Institute of Chicago, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Art Institute of Zanesville, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Ba-Be, General, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    (Jozef Bakos; Joseph Barber; Gifford Beal; Reynolds Beal; Rosalie Berkowitz)
  - Bl-Bu, General, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    (Louis Bouché)
  - Ca-Cl, General, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    (Albert Christ-Janer regarding his book Boardman Robinson)
  - Co-Cu, General, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    (Russell Cowles; Evangeline Cozzens; Currier Gallery of Art)
  - Carnegie Institute, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Cranbrook Academy of Art, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    (Albert Christ-Janer)
  - D, General, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    (Donald Greason of Deerfield Academy; Detroit Institute of Arts; Otis Dozier; Guy Pène Du Bois; Jacques Dubourg)
  - E, General, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - F, General, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    (Vaughn Flannery regarding a commission for Walter Jeffords; Emma L. Frankenberg)
  - Fausett, William Dean, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Fenster, Gershon, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Fine Arts Gallery of San Diego, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - G, General, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    (Ira Glackens; Earle Grant)
  - Wm. E. Goodridge & Son, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - Ha, General, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 28)
    (Jeanne Overbury Hart regarding George Overbury Hart drawings; Dalzell Hatfield)
  - He-Hu, General, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    (John Heliker; Fred Hornby)
  - Halberstadt, Ernst, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 30)
    (illustrated letter)
  - Hartell, John, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - J. L. Hudson Company, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 32)
  - I, General, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 33)
  - J, General, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 34)
  - K, General, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 35)
    (Charles Kaeselau; Henry G. Keller; William S. Kinney)
  - L, General, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 36)
    (Isabel Nagle Lachaise; Little House Galleries; Charles Locke)
  - Lahey, Richard, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 37)
  - Los Angeles County Museum, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 38)
  - M, General, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 39)
    (Milton McGreevy)
  - McBride, Lucia, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 40)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 41)
  - N, General, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 42)
  - O, General, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 43)
  - P, General, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 44)
    (Parrish Museum of Southampton; Charles Prendergast; Eugenie Prendergast)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 45)
  - Philadelphia Art Alliance, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 46)
  - Philadelphia Museum of Art, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 47)
  - R, General, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 48)
    (George Rickey; Iver Rose)
  - Robinson, Boardman, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 49)
  - Ruellan, Andrée, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 50)
  - Sa-Sl, General, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    (Henry E. Schnakenberg; Helen Farr Sloan; John Sloan enclosing a letter illustrated with a sketch of his studio)
  - Sm-Sy, General, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    (Vernon Smith including biographical information; State University of Iowa; illustrated letter from Katharine Sturgis)
  - T, General, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    (Thoroughbred Record correspondence annotated by Vaughn Flannery)
  - Toledo Museum of Art, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - U, General, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    (University of Chicago Press regarding publication of Boardman Robinson)
  - University of Nebraska, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - V, General, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Robert C. Vose Galleries, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    (William Dean Fausett exhibition)
  - W, General, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    (Alicia Waterson)
  - Williams, Esther, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - X-Y-Z, General, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    (Edmund Yaghjian; Linda Yates; Mahonri Mackintosh Young)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Receipts, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Ab-Ak, General, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    (Addison Gallery of Art; Akron Art Institute)
  - Al-Am, General, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    (establishing relationship with Humbert Albrizio; American Federation of Arts; establishing relationship with Bernard Arnest)
  - An-Au, General, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Art Institute of Chicago, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Ba-Bel, General, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    (Cecil Bell)
  - Ber-Bow, General, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    (Gifford Beal; Reynolds Beal; Rosalie Berkowitz; Lawrence Blazey; Louis Bouché)
  - Boy-Bu, General, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 20)
    (Buck Hill Art Association)
  - Biltmore Art Galleries, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Brooklyn Museum of Art, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Ca-Cl, General, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    (Marion Monks Chase)
  - Co-Cu, General, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 24)
    (Currier Gallery of Art regarding an Iver Rose exhibition)
  - Carnegie Institute, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Cleveland Museum of Art, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - Colorado Springs Fine Arts Center, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Cranbrook Academy of Art, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 29)
    (Albert Christ-Janer regarding a Boardman Robinson exhibition and sales of his book Boardman Robinson)
  - Da-Des, General, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 30)
    (Walt Dehner; Koren Der Harootian)
  - Dev-Dy, General, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 31)
    (establishing a relationship with Caroline Durieux)
  - Dartmouth College, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 32)
  - Detroit Institute of Arts, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 33)
  - Du Bois, Guy Pène, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 34)
  - E, General, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 35)
    (Kenneth Evett)
  - Fa-Find, General, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 36)
  - Fine-Fu, General, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 37)
  - Fausett, William Dean, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 38)
  - Flannery, Vaughn, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 39)
  - Ga-Gl, General, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 40)
    (Edith Glackens; Ira Glackens)
  - Go, General, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 41)
    (Lloyd Goff; Nelson Goodman; Katharine Sturgis Goodman)
  - Gr-Gu, General, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 42)
    (Grand Central Art Galleries)
  - Ha, General, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 43)
  - He-Hu, General, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 44)
    (John Heliker regarding his summer in Quebec)
  - Halberstadt, Ernst, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Hartell, John, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Hatfield, Dalzell, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Hooper, Parker Morse, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - J. L. Hudson Company, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - I, General, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - J, General, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - James, Oliver, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Jones, Alfred E., Jr., 1946 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - K, General, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - La-Leo, General, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    (Robert Laurent)
  - Lev-Lu, General, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Lahey, Richard, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Lambe, Polly, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Ma-Mc, General, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    (Reginald Marsh)
  - Me-Mu, General, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - McBride, Lucia, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - N, General, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    (City of New York second-hand dealers license with photographs of Antoinette and Charles Kraushaar)
  - O, General, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Pa-Pe, General, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    (James Penney)
  - Ph-Pu, General, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    (Charles Prendergast; Eugenie Prendergast)
  - Pepsi-Cola Company, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - R, General, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 23)
    (Sidney Raynes; Iver Rose)
  - Renaissance Society of the University of Chicago, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Robinson, Boardman, and Sally Robinson, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - Ruellan, Andrée, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - Sa-Sc, General, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - Se-So, General, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - Sp-Sy, General, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 29)
    (Gertrude Stack with a related letter from Louis Bouché)
  - Sloan, Helen Farr, and John Sloan, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - Smith, Vernon, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 31)
    (preparations for an exhibition containing details about his work)
  - Stanley, Alix W., 1946 (Box 28, Folder 32)
  - T, General, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 33)
  - Toledo Museum of Art, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 34)
  - Train, Helen, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 35)
  - U, General, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 36)
  - University of Chicago Press, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 37)
  - University of Nebraska, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 38)
  - V, General, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 39)
  - Robert C. Vose Galleries, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 40)
  - Wa-Wh, General, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 41)
    (illustrated letter from Michael Waskowsky)
  - Wi-Wy, General, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 42)
    (Wichita Art Museum)
  - Walker Art Center, 1946 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1946 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Wichita Art Museum, 1946 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Williams, Esther, 1946 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Willson, Donald B., 1946 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Worcester Art Museum, 1946 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - X-Y-Z, General, 1946 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    (Edmund Yaghjian regarding his move to Columbia, South Carolina, and briefly mentioning a visit from Rockwell Kent; Mahonri Mackintosh Young)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Receipts, 1946 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Ab-Am, General, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - An-Ay, General, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    (Bernard Arnest regarding his teaching job; Art Institute of Chicago)
  - Albrizio, Humbert, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Ba-Ber, General, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    (Rosalie Berkowitz concerning her new artwork)
  - Bes-Bo, General, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Br-Bu, General, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    (Branch Agricultural College of Utah; real estate agents Brown, Wheelock, Harris, & Stevens, Inc., documenting legal transfer of the business to Charles and Antoinette Kraushaar as of October 1; Buck Hill Art Association)
  - George Baer Galleries, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Beal, Gifford, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Ca-Ch, General, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    (Flavio Cabral; S. L. Charmin; Marion Monks Chase)
  - Ci-Coo, General, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Cor-Cu, General, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Carnegie Institute, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Cleveland Museum of Art, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Columbus Gallery of Fine Arts, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - Da, General, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 23)
    (Davenport Municipal Art Gallery in Iowa)
  - Dea-Det, General, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 24)
  - Dev-Dy, General, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 25)
    (Ross Devean; Guy Pène Du Bois concerning his decision to seek another dealer)
  - E, General, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 26)
    (Fritz Ehrenfest)
  - Evett, Kenneth, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 27)
  - F, General, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 28)
  - Fausett, William Dean, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 29)
  - Flannery, Vaughn, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 30)
  - Ga-Gl, General, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 31)
  - Go-Gr, General, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 32)
  - Glackens, Edith, and Ira Glackens, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 33)
  - Wm. E. Goodridge & Son, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 34)
  - Ha, General, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 35)
    (Charles Harsanyi; John Hartell)
  - He-Hu, General, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 36)
    (Alfred H. Holbrook of the University of Georgia Department of Art)
  - Halberstadt, Ernst, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 37)
  - Hatfield, Dalzell, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 38)
    (Russell Cowles exhibition)
  - Heliker, John, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    (summer spent in Quebec)
  - J. L. Hudson Company, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - I, General, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - J, General, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    (Walter Jeffords)
  - K, General, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Keighley, Genevieve, and William Keighley, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - La-Le, General, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    (Richard Lahey; William F. Laporte; Genevieve Lawrence)
  - Li-Lu, General, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    (Robert E. Locher)
  - Laurent, Robert, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Levyne, Sidney A., 1947 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Ma-Mc, General, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Me-Mi, General, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Mo-Mu, General, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - May, George, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Minneapolis Institute of Arts, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - N, General, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - O, General, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Charles Z. Offin Advertising, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Pa-Pen, General, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Pep-Pu, General, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 20)
    (Duncan Phillips)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Portraits, Inc., 1947 (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Prendergast, Charles, and Eugenie Prendergast, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 23)
    (exhibition of Charles Prendergast's work; issues relating to the settlement of John F. Kraushaar's estate)
  - Q, General, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - R, General, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 25)
    (Randolph-Macon Woman's College; Sidney Raynes; Renaissance Society of the University of Chicago; Iver Rose; Alice Roullier concerning the closing of Albert Roullier Art Galleries)
  - Robinson, Boardman, and Sally Robinson, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 26)
    (Boardman Robinson's poor health following a stroke)
  - Ruellan, Andrée, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 27)
  - Sa-Sm, General, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 28)
    (Henry E. Schnakenberg; Karl Schrag)
  - So-Sy, General, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 29)
  - Charles Sessler, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 30)
  - Sloan, Helen Farr, and John Sloan, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 31)
  - Smith, Vernon, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 32)
  - J. B. Speed Memorial Museum, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 33)
  - Stanley, Alix W., 1947 (Box 30, Folder 34)
  - T, General, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 35)
  - Toledo Museum of Art, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 36)
  - Train, Helen, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 37)
  - U, General, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 38)
  - University of Nebraska, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 39)
  - V, General, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 40)
  - Robert C. Vose Galleries, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 41)
  - Wa-Wh, General, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 42)
  - Wi-Wo, General, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 43)
    (Wichita Art Museum; Lewis B. Williams regarding a portrait by John Koch; Ralph L. Wilson)
  - Wadsworth Atheneum, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 44)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 45)
  - Williams, Esther, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 46)
    (family matters and her artwork)
  - Witte Memorial Museum, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 47)
  - Worcester Art Museum, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 48)
  - X-Y-Z, General, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 49)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Receipts, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 50)
    (price list for commissioned portraits by William Dean Fausett, John Koch, and Esther Williams)
  - Ab-Am, General, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    (Humbert Albrizio)
  - An-Ay, General, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Arnest, Bernard, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Art in Industry, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    (agreements with various artists giving exclusive option for use of their work in the design and decoration of industrial products for a year)
  - Art Institute of Chicago, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Ba, General, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    (Peggy Bacon; Joseph Barber)
  - Be, General, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Bi-Bu, General, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Beal, Becky, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Bouché, Louis, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Ca-Ch, General, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    (Francis Chapin; S. L. Charmin; Edward Christiana)
  - Ci-Cu, General, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    (Cincinnati Art Museum; Russell Cowles)